SUNDAY
11:40 PM
"Why didn’t you call me, huh?"
Why?
"Where the heck were you?"
Where the heck?
62 HOURS OF ROBBERY
Wounded man! Wounded man! Help me!
"What happened?"
Helsinki, what happened?
Hostages, escape.
Strong whack, brain injury.
Denver, did you know about the escape?
Which hostage did the escape?
Arturo. He told me, but I...
didn’t get there in time.
Arturo.
Helsinki.
Oslo is not well.
No.
He’s badly injured.
No, no.
Not badly injured.
He just needs rest and medicine.
Time for medicine.
-Why has he got his eyes opened?
-I, now give medicine.
Anti-inflammatories
and heparin.
And go to sleep.
And tomorrow, Oslo better.
Moscow, you don’t worry.
Oslo and I have had
worst colds than this one.
Worst colds.
"Oslo’s eyes never twinkled,
but now it was how we looked all of us,
sad and absent.
Hope is like dominoes,
once one falls, the others follow.
And the hostages noticed we were fucked."
Last night we heard the shots.
Anyone injured?
I won’t shut my mouth.
-Sit down.
-One of my pupils is missing,
Pablo Ruiz,
and I want to know where he is.
Sit down.
I said sit down!
Your pupil escaped
with a group of hostages.
They blew up a charge and fled.
You don’t have to worry about anyone.
They’re all fine.
What’s that freak doing?
Madam, sit down
and stop clapping your hands.
Sit down.
Sit down, now!
Madam, sit down.
To the ground.
To the ground!
For fuck’s sake,
everyone to the ground, damn!
To the ground!
Sit down!
Fucking hell, to the ground!
Make them stop.
Stop!
I said, stop!
Everyone sit down.
Sit down.
Sit down, please.
Well, look.
No, Moscow.
-What?
-First, open eyes.
Look where shoot.
Hold gun.
Relax elbow.
-But, you wear thongs, don’t you?
-I’m not going to wear knickers.
-I’m not wearing, I left it at home.
-No.
Then neither will I.
-With a bare cock you rob.
-Don’t’ be dirty-minded.
-Bare cock.
-The hostages...
Quiet.
What’s the matter?
As time progresses
the hostages will stop being compliant.
When they see there are no releases,
that there isn’t any progress,
their survival instinct
will make them do something.
And what will they do?
The Numismatics people will do
like de Bruce Willis?
Something of that sort, Nairobi.
They’ll try to escape.
Or they’ll escape.
-No.
-That’s possible, it can happen.
We’re armed.
At that point, the other hostages
will stop fearing us.
If that happens, it’s extremely important
to regain control and, in that case,
we’ll do it using empathy,
creating an atmosphere
of much more solid trust than the one
we’ve had until to that moment.
Trust and M-16,
don’t go together, do they?
Then we’ll have to find things
that bring us closer to the hostages.
Let’s see.
What unites people, huh?
Football.
Football is a good example.
But there’s something
that unites people ever more
than football.
Sex?
Yes, sex brings people together,
but in couples.
-Or not.
-Careful.
Usually.
There’s... There are, well...
There are threesomes and even foursomes
-and even structures of group.
-Structures?
But it goes without saying
that there’s no room for that
-in our plan.
-Ay, sorry, guys.
Thank goodness.
With my luck, if we organize an orgy,
I’m sure I’ll have this one behind.
But, Professor,
what unites more than sex?
What unites us?
All of us, I mean.
Well, I’ve become very fond
of you all, but, honestly,
money.
Money.
And we might not have other things,
but we’ll have loads of money.
I’ve been giving it a lot of thought
about how to turn our hostages
into our business partners.
And, well, I’ve come to the conclusion.
Money
or freedom.
Have you ever thought,
I mean like in fantasy,
of putting price to yourself?
I’m telling you I'm in.
Think it over, Mr Torres,
you’ve got two hours.
I have nothing to think over.
I’m talking about the pain,
the pain we’re causing you.
I’m working here better
than I’ve ever worked in my whole life.
What would be a hostage’s minimum salary?
I thought of a million euros,
Just like that, tax free.
You won’t fool me.
-I know perfectly how this works.
-Really?
You know how hard it is,
and you know that your profession
is something that’s in your blood.
I’ve never had a boss like you,
Ms Nairobi.
It's that or the second option.
-Which is the second option?
-Leave just like that, with nothing.
Like I’m telling you, but empty handed.
How will we get
a million euros out of here?
Hidden inside our underwear?
You give me the address
of a first cousin’s of yours, a friend,
and I’ll make sure you receive an envelope
with your money in five, or six months
-after getting out of here.
-Think it over.
It’s different to raise a son
with a million under your mattress.
So...
Freedom
or the money.
One million.
There was a camera,
at the toilets entrance.
And in this corridor
I think there was another one.
So you say that apart from the building
cameras, they installed some more.
Yes, those ones were different.
We were digging a tunnel for them.
It was in the basement.
There was a lot of ammunition.
Enough for a war,
there were boxes full of bullets,
chargers, explosives.
Yes, these three were part of the gang.
They were eight, two of them foreigners.
Could you say if any of them
was the Professor?
Their names were city names.
Berlin.
-Moscow.
-Denver.
-Nairobi.
-Helsinki.
-She is Tokyo.
-This one was Rio.
He was the least dangerous of them.
He was watching Alison.
Was Alison in a different place
from the rest of the hostages?
Yes, sometimes she was taken apart.
One of the foreigners is injured
or dead.
We hit him on the head with a pipe.
Oslo was his name.
If you’ll excuse me, you can have a rest.
You may have a coffee or something to eat.
-Okay.
-Lobo, escort him outside.
Have a sit.
These are Ángel’s glasses.
They inserted a microphone in them,
a Keylock 20-10
with an audio range of 1,500 metres.
They must have done it
when he went in with the paramedics.
Ángel is not a traitor.
Raquel.
I know what’s crossing
your mind right now.
But you were just doing your job.
Any of us would have done the same.
All the evidence pointed at him.
I was also wrong.
THE SECOND IN CHARGE
OF THE HEIST CRISIS
OF THE FÁBRICA DE MONEDA Y TIMBRE
IN COMMA AFTER HAVING
A CAR ACCIDENT
"You have a new message.
Raquel, it’s me again.
Phone me, your voice mailbox is full.
We have him, listen, we have him.
We have the guy
who is helping them from outside.
Yes, it’s Salva, Salva.
Salva, the one that makes cider.
He was in the wreck yard.
He threatened the Russian guy.
For heaven’s sake, he’s using you, damn.
His fingerprints are in the patrol car.
He’s got closer to you
to learn about the investigation.
He’s using you.
To return the phone call press...."
"Hello, it’s Raquel.
I can answer you right now.
If it’s urgent,
leave your message after the beep."
"The voice mailbox of the number
you have dialled is full."
Ángel was phoning me all evening,
But I didn’t pick up his phone calls.
Sixteen phone calls.
He phoned me 16 times.
And I didn’t answer the phone.
"Raquel.
Raquel, it’s Ángel.
Listen to me,
I’m asking you to reconsider.
Look, I can understand your rage.
-I’ve also...."
-Unplug the loudspeaker or turn it down.
"...the first row we’ve had.
I must be an asshole
or whatever you say,"
but I’m not the mole.
I’m not the mole, for heaven’s sake.
"You’ll ruin my life, Raquel.
Phone me.
Raquel."
Why the heck you don’t pick up?
Huh? After 15 year with you,
"besides you like a fucking fool.
And not to get closer to you,
no, because of friendship."
Because of love, do you hear me?
"Because of love.
I’d been very close
to breaking up with everything,"
To ditching Mari Carmen for a bitch
that not even Prieto would fuck.
"Do you hear me? Yes, you’re a bitch."
A selfish and obsessive bitch.
You’re a fucking bitch, a fucking bitch.
A cunt licker.
"A frigid, for fuck’s sake, a...."
"How many punches can you take
before falling on the canvass?
If you are Raquel Murillo, many.
But there’s something wrong in being good
at rolling with the punches."
"Attention, inspector Murillo
is approaching the front wall."
"If the punches don’t cease,
you’ll end up falling down the same.
And when you fall down,
it’ll be as all the punches
were received at the same time."
Raquel!
-Raquel!
"Murillo stopped hearing,
stopped thinking.
She just walked on.
It was an empty body
searching for all that to end."
Raquel!
Come!
Let’s go, let’s go!
Excuse me, I didn’t quite understand.
Freedom.
-I said I want...
-No, no.
Wait, before you give me
an answer seriously, I want...
I would like to you to take into account
a couple considerations.
The first one is...
You must consider
that you and I have a relationship.
And the second
is that freedom carries
a lot of un unexpected situations,
risks and terrible things, perhaps,
that for me, personally, are scary.
Do you know that eagle chicks
fall off before the right time
and crash on to the rocks?
That makes me scared.
Or baby rabbits, leverets,
that are in their dens.
They see the sunlight,
and come out,
and a wolf breaks their neck in one bite.
That makes me scared.
No, Ariadna? Because...
Perhaps now,
at this particular moment, leaving is
far more dangerous
than staying.
And I wouldn’t like that anything bad
happened to you, Ariadna.
I don’t want you
to become distressed, either.
I don’t want that. I’ll give you
two hours to think about it.
I must leave.
I’m pregnant,
I need to see a gynaecologist,
well, also the orthopaedic surgeon.
Or whatever doctor you see, I don’t know
which specialist I have to see
for a bullet wound in your leg.
It’ll be the internal medicine doctor,
won’t it? I don’t know.
Let’s see, what’s wrong?
The million euros is not appealing enough?
-With that money you can leave ever after.
-It depends.
If the wound becomes gangrenous
and I end up limping...
If that happens,
we’ll think of what to do.
You don’t need to expect for the worst.
I should think.
Besides, you’re very well here,
aren’t you?
You’ve got your own bedroom, Mónica
Gaztambide’s Presidential suite, or not?
You might even miss us...
if you go.
Why are you insisting on me staying?
You won’t have fallen in love,
haven’t you?
It’s not true.
Listen, look at me, are you serious?
-So what if I am serious?
-Let’s see.
-You can’t fall in love in 60 hours.
-Well, in 60 hours.
In 60 hours I shot you,
I extracted the bullet.
You found out you were pregnant,
now abortion yes, abortion no,
shall I break up with my boyfriend.
You have sex with me.
If you give 24 more hours,
I might ask you to marry me.
And then 24 hours later, we get a divorce.
What the fuck does time matter
inside here?
-In the end time is something that...
-All right.
All right, what?
I’ll stay.
But to get married and that
you’ll have to give a little more time.
I don’t know, 16 minutes or so.
RAQUEL’S UNKNOWN’S TELEPHONE
Hello?
Sorry to phone you again.
It’s Raquel’s mother.
As the other day you were
so close to my daughter,
you see, I have an urgent message
from detective Ángel.
"And I can’t get through to her.
Are you near her?"
Not now,
but I’ll be seeing her in a moment.
"If you tell me,
I may be able to talk to her."
Thank you ever so much,
because it seemed important.
What message?
I’ll read it for you.
Yes, "we have him, we have the fucking guy
"who is helping them from outside.
It’s the guy that makes cider,
the one who was in the wreck yard,
the one who threatened"
the Russian guy", one second.
"His fingerprints were in the patrol car.
We have him.
I’m on my way to the tent
and I’ll tell you everything."
Have you written all down?
Yes, don’t worry.
-"I’ll take care of it."
-Well, thank you very much again.
-"Thank you so much."
-You’re welcome.
"The Professor had built a plan down
to the last millimetre.
Each movement of the police,
any possible mistake from his gang,
the hostages’ behaviour,
each variable, everything,
And then, when he thought
everything was under his control,
he found out that it wasn’t so.
It would have never crossed his mind
that to avoid the whole plan
going down the toilet,
he would have to kill.
Kill the mother of the woman
he was falling in love with.
And, of course,
no one is prepared for that."
What did you give me?
An intravenous sedative.
Have you already spoken to the hostages?
What did they say?
So far they’ve confirmed
that they’re building a tunnel.
We’re going to locate the exact position.
And what we already know,
that they are armed up to the teeth.
Raquel.
You’re the most qualified person
to lead this operation,
but it’s high time you had a rest.
Don’t worry about anything.
The superintendent is on his way
to substitute you.
So you can go home for a few hours.
You have to sleep.
Can I make a phone call?
Sure.
Here.
"Salva, it’s Raquel."
Look, I need you to come over
to get me out of here.
This is the worst day of my life"
and I have to get away from this tent,
from this city.
Salva, are you there?
I can’t, there’s something I have to do.
Sure, sure, I understand.
"To phone like this
is a bit...."
-Good morning.
-Hello.
Can I help you?
I’m Salva, your daughter’s friend.
-We spoke on the phone.
-Yes, yes, of course.
Come in, come in.
Thank you.
Come in.
He’s not reacting.
I don’t want to be pessimistic,
but I’m afraid his brain injury
has caused irreversible damage.
What? Are you a neurosurgeon?
We don’t know.
We must take him to a hospital.
He might still have a chance to be cured.
No one leaves.
Do you hear me? With hole or not hole.
-You know what the Professor said.
-I couldn’t care less about the Professor.
Where was the Professor
when the 16 hostages were escaping?
Where was he
when they smashed Oslo’s head?
We open the doors, call the police and let
the paramedics come and take him out.
What the fuck are you talking about?
The rules were clear, no one goes out.
We all agreed, Oslo too.
16 hostages have escaped.
The rules have changed.
The hostages don’t know
what’s happening here, Oslo does.
And so, huh? If he can’t even speak.
Even if he could he wouldn’t betray us.
Damn, let’s vote.
This isn’t a nice democracy.
It isn’t, no.
We open the doors
and we let Oslo out.
No one is leaving.
Berlin.
Oslo isn’t leaving.
Me speak with Oslo before entering.
Wound doesn’t matter.
Death before prison.
You understand?
Yes.
Me take care of Oslo.
I must say, you have a beautiful house.
Thank you very much.
Raquel is not at home.
Poor her, she works so hard...
I was having a coffee.
Would you like to take one?
-I wouldn’t like to bother you.
-It’ll only take me a few minutes.
-Ah, then, thank you very much.
-Very well. Have a seat.
"There are 10,000 ways
to kill an elderly woman,
but the Professor was no hit man.
He was more of a chess player
for whom the world of crime was too big.
So he chose a cleaner
and more intelligent option.
Pour 2.5 milligrams of dioxin
into the old lady’s coffee,
wait until the cardiac arrest
occurred due to the drug
and vanish."
Any sugar?
Yes, please, three spoonful.
You have a sweet tooth, haven’t you?
So have I.
But I shouldn’t.
"Three sugar spoonful and one of dioxin.
In 15 minutes time
she would have a heart attack.
In 30 minutes Raquel
would find her mother’s body.
In an hour, a coroner
would authorize the removal of the body
as it was a cardiovascular heart attack.
No signs of violence,
the victim’s age, the door closed,
inside her home.
There would be no autopsy,
and the Professor knew it."
Thank you.
"Clean and simple."
My daughter didn’t come home last night.
Was she with you?
Well...
Well, actually, she was.
Yesterday we met.
Well.
Did you make love?
Well...
Actually we did.
I’m glad.
Sorry for prying into your life,
but I’m really glad.
My daughter desperately needs to be loved
and someone to make love to her.
And a man who is a good man.
And you seem a good man.
I can see it in your eyes.
Excuse me.
I’ve dropped it.
As we get older we become clumsy...
Excuse me.
Oslo won’t speak again.
I’m very sorry, it’s...
-It’s very tragic.
-You knew about escape?
No.
Denver tell me.
You knew about escape.
Know as such, I didn’t know.
I could hint something,
and I told Denver to help.
They hit him with this pipe
behind back.
Oslo friend.
Me and Oslo, together in war,
peace together,
robberies together,
prison together.
Oslo friend.
You understand, Arturo?
On your knees.
Did you really think
we wouldn’t try to escape,
that we wouldn’t defend ourselves,
that we would stand there
watching how you killed us,
how you tortured us, how you raped us?
One and a thousand times
I would do it again.
If you’re going to do it, hit me hard,
because if you don’t kill me,
I might kill you afterwards.
I came to work
as any other day
without harming anyone,
only to fulfil my duty.
Who do you think the good guys are,
Helsinki?
You?
Finish quickly, please.
Bring me over the dustpan and the mop,
they are there, in that corner, please.
Thank you.
I’ll do it.
"I don’t live in Almazán now,
I live in Madrid.
I have two daughters: Raquel y Laura.
I’ll never go to an old people home.
Raquel is a serious woman,
but she loves me very much."
Excuse me?
"We have him, it’s the cider guy.
His fingerprints were in the patrol car."
-Do you mind if I make a phone call?
-No, of course not.
"Raquel, it’s me again.
Phone me, your voice mailbox is full.
We have him, listen, we have him.
We have the guy
who is helping them from outside.
Yes, it’s Salva, Salva.
Salva, the guy who makes cider.
He was in the wreck yard,
he threatened the Russian guy.
For fuck’s sake, he’s using you, damn.
His fingerprints are in the patrol car.
He’s getting close to you
to know about the investigation.
If you wish to hear the message again,
press 1.
To delete it, press 2.
To save it, press...
Message deleted.
There are no more messages."
No one is answering.
Salva?
But what are you doing here?
This was the thing I had to do.
The only thing, I left your garden
in a really bad state.
Isn’t he adorable?
He’s already told me
you made love.
-Mum.
-What?
I didn’t say anything,
she must have suspected it.
Time to eat.
-Would like some pudding?
-Well, I’ll have to taste them.
If there as tasty as this soup.
It’s the best one I’ve ever tasted
-in a very long time.
-Thank you.
Darling, don’t play with your food.
You’re hardly eating anything.
It’s that job.
It makes her very stressed.
-The kidnapping, have you heard about it?
-Yes.
You’re telling me.
I follow it constantly,
I’m following it in the press.
It’s terrible what’s happening.
I’m all worried.
There was some shooting
inside yesterday, huh?
Wasn’t there, and some explosions.
No, I really...
those people armed to the teeth...
Who knows, any day,
some horrific thing will happen.
"There was shooting yesterday.
Armed to the teeth.
They have at least three M-16.
A Browning ground machine gun.
Retroxil, is a medicine.
In Toledo there has been
an unusual demand."
-Where was the last purchase?
-Here, in Palomeque.
18th of October.
Excuse me, I have to make a phone call.
But, darling...
Every day the same.
Suárez, put me on speakers.
Connect my mobile to the loud speakers.
We have communication with the Inspector.
-Turn it up.
-Well, listen up everyone.
I need you to look for
"all the rural estates
where hunting is allowed"
within 100 kilometres distance
from the pharmacy in Palomeque.
I want a map of Toledo now.
Look for a map,
-perimeter of Palomeque.
-"If they bought the medicines there,"
it means that they were close.
Fuck, how didn’t I realize sooner?
Because they need a place
where they could organize it, where they
could prepare their plan step by step.
They had to do target practice
before entering the Fábrica,
somewhere where the shots and detonations
wouldn’t raise any alarms.
I want some units canvassing
the perimeter of Palomeque
within 100 kilometres, I want them now.
Documentation.
It must be a 100 hectares rural estate.
Look it up in the land registry.
With a house in it.
-Suárez, call me when you find something.
-I will.
You heard her. We have no time to waste,
let’s get them, okay?
That estate, those units.
I want it all, I want it now.
Yes?
Are you all right?
Yes, a bit tired. Come in.
And dazed too.
They had to inject me a sedative
and, the truth, I’m not used to.
I see, I’m not very clearheaded today,
either.
You’ll excuse me, Salva, but I need
to lie down. I need to get some sleep.
Sure, sure.
It’s the time now to make a decision.
You have to choose between being
accomplices and getting a million euros
or being upright people and leaving.
Freedom
or one million euros.
If you stay with us
to see the end of this,
you’ll receive, at home,
20,000 banknotes of 50 euros,
in an air-tight bag
like good ham.
Those who want to leave,
please, cross the line.
What will we do
with those who choose their freedom?
You’ll take them downstairs
to the Fábrica basement
and lock them up there.
I know it’s terrible, but...
precisely those are the ones
that could actually try to rise up
another rebellion.
And I need to protect you.
Why can’t I choose to leave?
Because you’re our top hostage, darling.
Really?
Do we need to explain it to you?
Move aside, you’re in the way.
Okay, time is ticking. Now or never.
You can either cross the line
and leave
or stay with us
and your million euros.
Very good.
Those wanting to leave,
put your hands on your head.
Move forward, through the door
to the loading area.
"What the Professor had gained
was to divide the hostages
into those who would become our partners
and those who could still
complicate things.
At least that’s what we thought.
Yes, Suárez.
Inspector, we have a rural estate.
It matches perfectly the description.
-Where is it?
-"Near Palomeque",
the small town where the pharmacy is.
It’s 640 hectares
"and it’s a private hunting land.
There’s a house too"
big enough to plan a heist
of that magnitude.
-How did you find it?
-"A neighbour in the area
saw a group of youngsters
on the evening of San Juan.
"They didn’t look like hunters,
but all through the summer
-he heard explosions."
-Explosions.
Yes, explosions.
He doesn’t quite know what they were,
"but he’s sure they weren’t
hunting rifles, not with cartridge ."
I send units to the area
and arrange for an intervention team
-"for a possible armed intervention."
-Very good.
Send me the information to my mobile.
As soon as I can I’ll head there.
Lobo, we have the all clear,
we’re setting off.
Units 1, 2 and 3 ready, now!
Salva, look, I’m not feeling well.
Can you drive?
-Yes.
-I need you to drive me to a place.
Everything starts tomorrow.
Sergio.
I want you to promise me one thing.
If things go wrong,
you’ll run away.
You won’t be waiting at the hangar.
Nothing will go wrong.
You know, as I do,
that everything could go wrong.
I’ll only go there if you promise me
that, if things are shot to hell,
you won’t let them catch you.
I won’t promise you that.
Either you promise me now or you won’t
have a captain in charge from now on.
You already know me.
Nothing will go wrong, Andrés.
We’re the Resistance, aren’t we?
"The Professor’s whole life
revolved around just one idea:
Resistance.
His grandfather,
who had resisted next to the partisans
to defeat the fascists in Italia
had taught him that song.
And later on
he taught us."
Six kilometres straight on, and after
the first diversion on the right.
Salva, can you drive a little faster.
You won’t be fined being with me.
You’re driving at 40 km/h.
Yes, true, I’m sorry.
I’m a bit dense today.
Wait for me here.
On the left side
and on the right side too.
No one comes in without wearing a suit.
Whoever is not essential here
stay out of perimeter 1.
"Is it clear?
It’s clear."
We hit the jackpot.
There’s DNA of every type.
"I want the photographers
and the Scientific branch in.
Take photographs of everything."
The whole house has to be raided,
every single corner.
"We are on the first floor.
There’s an attic. It’s amazing.
You won’t believe what we’ve found."
Inspector.
You have to see this.
The whole thing is on the walls.
Timetables, photos, maps.
The whole fucking plan.
We have it, sirs.
"Their time is over."
TO BE CONTINUED